The story of Arthur the Rat. Once upon a time there was a young rat who couldn't
make up his mind. Whenever the other rat says to him if he would like to come out
hunting with them, he would answer in a hoarse voice.
I don't know and when they said would you rather stay inside? He would say yes or
No, either he'd always
Shake making your choice
one fine day
His Aunt Josephine said to him,
Now look here, no one will ever care for you if you carry on like this.
You have no more mind of your own than a greasy old blade of grass.
The young rat coughed and looked quiet as usual, but said nothing.
think so," said his aunt, stamping her foot, for she couldn't bear to see the young rat
so cold-blooded. I don't know was all he ever answered, and then he walked off to
think.
for an hour or more. Rather he would stay in his hole in the ground or go out into the loft.
One night the rats heard a loud noise in the loft. It was a very dreary old clock.
The roof let the rain come down, come washing in.
The beams and the rafters had all rotted through, so the whole thing was quite unsafe.
At last, one of the joists gave way.
and the beams fell with one edge on the floor.
The walls shook, the cupola fell off,
and all the rats' hair stood on end with fear and horror.
This won't do, said the leader, we can't stay cooped up here any longer, so they sent out scouts to search for a new home.
A little later on that evening, the scouts come back and said they had found an old-fashioned horse farm.
where there would be room for all of them.
The leader gave the order at once,
come you fallen in.
And the rats crawled out of the hole right away
and stood on the floor in a long line.
Just then the old rat caught sight of young Arthur.
That was the name of the shaker.
He wasn't in the line, and he wasn't exactly outside it.
He stood just by it.
Come on, get in line, growled the old rat coarsely.
Of course you're coming too. I don't know, said Arthur calmly, why the idea of it.
You don't think it's safe here anymore, do you?
I'm not certain, said Arthur undaunted.
The roof may not fall down yet.
Well, said the old rat, you can't wait for you to join us.
Then he turned to the other and shouted, right about the face, march.
And the long line marched out.
born while a young rat watched him. I think I'll go tomorrow, he said to himself, but then again
perhaps I won't. It's so nice and snug here. I guess I'll go back to my hole under the log for a while.
just to make up my mind, but during the night there was a big crash.
Down came beams, rafters, joists, the whole business.
Next morning, it was a foggy day, some men came to look over the damage.
It seemed odd to them that the old building was not haunted by rats, but at last one of
them happened to move aboard, and he caught sight of a young rat, quite dead, half in
and half out of his hole.
Thus, the shirker got his due, and there was no more.
morning for him.